U.S. Wage Stabilization Board Documents 5476
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Wage Stabilization Board Documents
1921-1962
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
United States. Wage Stabilization Board
5476
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Case files, records (documents).
Materials of the U.S. Wage Stabilization Board include memoranda and press releases concerning wage policy, union security, procedures for handling cases, and national defense.
2299573
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The United States Wage Stabilization Board was created as an agency of the Economic Stabilization Agency by executive order under the authority of the Defense Production Act of 1950. Its function was to control wages during the Korean War. An executive order, 1951, reestablished the Board with power to assist the president in settling industrial disputes. In July, 1952, the Board was reconstituted under legislative authority and stripped of its functions in the area of labor disputes. It was terminated April 30, 1953.
Scope and Contents
Materials of the U.S. Wage Stabilization Board include memoranda and press releases concerning wage policy, union security, procedures for handling cases, and national defense.
Also, panel reports and recommendations, answers, statements and briefs pertaining to the labor dispute settlement case of the United Steelworkers of America vs. various steel and iron ore companies (1952) on issues of shift differential, vacation, holiday, ability to pay, profits, geographic wage differentials, management rights, working conditions, contracting out, seniority, arbitration procedure, wage adjustment, productivity, union security, and wage differential.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Korean War, 1950-1953 -- Economic aspects -- United States; Wage-price policy -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial. Steel industry. United States.; Contracting out. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Labor disputes. Steel industry. United States.; Labor productivity. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Management rights. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Seniority, Employee. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Steel industry. United States. Military aspects.; Trade-union security. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Wages. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; Wages. Steel industry. United States.; Wages. United States. State supervision.; Working conditions. Arbitration, Industrial. United States.; United States. Wage Stabilization Board.; United Steelworkers of America
2299573
- Inland Steel v. National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- International Harvester Arbitration Decisions, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- National War Labor Board, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Wage Stabilization Board, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Scope and Contents
  United Steelworkers exhibits
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Wage Stabilization Board in matter between United Steelworkers and various steel and ore companies, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- War Production Board, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous reports and printed materials, 1921-1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)